<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stephen Geinosky</title>
    <description>I am a full-stack web developer who finds beauty in minimalism. I currently work for NCAR, and work on giving our users the best experience possible.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:41:01 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:41:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project 4</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With a team of developers and stakeholders, I helped implemented a complete redesign of three umbrella websites as part using Scrum. As part of the development team, we identified a list of user profiles and worked with a team of content editors to restructure the umbrella website content. We then worked with a team of outside designers to finalize a new theme for the websites. After we were handed off the new design, I worked with the team to fully implement the new design into three Drupal 8 websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When working solo, I use the Kanban method to track products from conception to completion. Since implementing this workflow, I have seen a drastic increase both productivity and increased awareness of a current product’s state with product owners. While I have tried several Kanban board tools, I have found JIRA to be the most flexible. Especially as I transition from individual work and group work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/25/project-4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/25/project-4/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project 3</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;national-center-for-atmospheric-research&quot;&gt;National Center for Atmospheric Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-developer-iii&quot;&gt;Web Developer III&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using Agile, implemented a complete redesign of three umbrella websites as part of a development team from initial content structure and design concepts to the development design phase and implementation&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Improved web accessibility from an average score of 68% on Google Lighthouse to over 90% on the new responsive umbrella websites&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-developer-iigraphic-designer&quot;&gt;Web Developer II/Graphic Designer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Performing a UX audit/improvements on the content editor interface on the CISL Drupal website&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Utilized Google Analytics to direct front-end improvements&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Working with staff to restructure group content with a focus on user experience within CISL&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Train staff on any updates/changes/improvements made to the uploading and editing content process&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Redesigned main menu in the sub-theme to improve usability&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;harvard-magazine&quot;&gt;Harvard Magazine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;associate-web-developer&quot;&gt;Associate Web Developer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Utilized Google Analytics to help filter out trending pages, topics, and events such as email blasts visited on the website to help target advertising opportunities&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Trained staff on any updates/changes/improvements made to the uploading and editing content process&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Restructured our content and gave a training seminar to local staff on SEO best practices and improvements&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/25/project-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/25/project-3/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project 2</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;national-center-for-atmospheric-research&quot;&gt;National Center for Atmospheric Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-developer-iii&quot;&gt;Web Developer III&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Developed and manage a custom Drupal 8 Composer upstream and custom Drupal 7 upstream on Pantheon&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Manage CircleCI configuration to automate the publication of our custom Drupal distributions&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Created and maintain custom Drupal modules for daily email campaigns, content migration, custom theming, and a public alert system&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consistently look for areas of automation and development improvements&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Moved sites from in-house hosting to Pantheon and AWS&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Performing security updates on multiple Drupal websites&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-developer-iigraphic-designer&quot;&gt;Web Developer II/Graphic Designer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Built a module leveraging an API to create automated organizational charts using OOP&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Added additional security measures to a custom authentication module&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Built a module to create an additional role and assign authenticated users the role to be used on the ucar.edu and president.ucar.edu Drupal sites&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Organized and led a group to restructure CISL’s website sitemap&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Updated content, cleaned up code and file structure on a kiosk&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Migrate remaining Drupal 6 sites to Drupal 7 using the migrate module&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Built a blog and documentation website on Gitpages&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Performing security updates on multiple Drupal websites&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;harvard-magazine&quot;&gt;Harvard Magazine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;associate-web-developer&quot;&gt;Associate Web Developer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Completely rebuilt Harvard Magazine’s classifieds section and their classifieds purchase form with Ubercart&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Restructured how classified ads are stored in the database and displayed to the user&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maintained custom .bash script that created daily back-ups of databases&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/25/project-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/25/project-2/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project 1</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;national-center-for-atmospheric-research&quot;&gt;National Center for Atmospheric Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-developer-iii&quot;&gt;Web Developer III&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Refactored a responsive front-end base theme applicable to multiple applications that utilizes Foundation, reduced package manager complexity, and cleaned template and SASS redundancy&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Implemented BackstopJS to reduce errors through visual-regression-testing&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Developed a static website friendsofthenationalcenter.org using Bootstrap&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-developer-iigraphic-designer&quot;&gt;Web Developer II/Graphic Designer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Working with staff to restructure group content with a focus on user experience&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Designed a sub-theme improving usability using analytics and user tests&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maintaining current theme&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Built a blog and documentation website on Github pages&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Built a custom MailChimp template&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Updated content, refactored XML code and file structure for a touchscreen kiosk&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;harvard-magazine&quot;&gt;Harvard Magazine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;associate-web-developer&quot;&gt;Associate Web Developer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Redesigned article pages to create a better reading experience by focusing on the text and images&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Created a custom landing page theme that can be used to promote special events&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Created a custom module to help allow the magazine to customize content based upon a custom taxonomy&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Custom-built floating and pushdown ads that utilize a cookie to only display the ads during scheduled intervals to users&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Added a custom classifieds blog within the site&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Designed a cleaner navigation focusing on usability and functionality&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Completely rebuilt Harvard Magazine’s donor section from the ground up&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Added features, including an interactive chart and a landing page dedicated to current and potential donors&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Built several custom-themed email templates in MailChimp for the over 200,000 email recipients&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/25/project-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/25/project-1/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
