<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stephen Geinosky</title>
    <description>I am a web developer/designer who finds beauty in minimalism. I currently work for NCAR, and work on giving our users the best experience possible.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 16:14:51 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 16:14:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project 1</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;cislncar&quot;&gt;CISL/NCAR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-developer-iigraphic-designer&quot;&gt;Web Developer II/Graphic Designer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designed a sub-theme improving usability using analytics and user tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Organized and led a group to restructure the website’s sitemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Working with communications department to build a custom responsive theme to be used organization wide&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maintaining current theme&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Working with staff to restructure group content with a focus on user experience&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Built a custom MailChimp template&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Updated content, cleaned up code and file structure on a kiosk&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;harvard-magazine&quot;&gt;Harvard Magazine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;associate-web-developer&quot;&gt;Associate Web Developer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Redesigned article pages to create a better reading experience by focusing on the text and images&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Created a custom landing page theme that can be used to promote special events&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Created a custom module to help allow the magazine to customize content based upon a custom taxonomy&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Custom-built floating and pushdown ads that utilize a cookie to only display the ads during scheduled intervals to users&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Added a custom classifieds blog within the site&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Designed a cleaner navigation focusing on usability and functionality&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Completely rebuilt Harvard Magazine’s donor section from the ground up&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Added features, including an interactive chart and a landing page dedicated to current and potential donors&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Built several custom-themed email templates in MailChimp for the over 200,000 email recipients&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;freelance-web-designer&quot;&gt;Freelance Web Designer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Designed and coded an interactive, Flash-based website for local band “It’s All Good” focusing on new elements to reach out to potential listeners and venues&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Designed and developed Drupal website for local Boy Scout Troop&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Designed a Tumblr website for “497 lessons I wish my coach had taught me”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/10/22/project-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/10/22/project-1/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project 2</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;cislncar&quot;&gt;CISL/NCAR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-developer-iigraphic-designer&quot;&gt;Web Developer II/Graphic Designer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Migrate remaining Drupal 6 sites to Drupal 7 using the migrate module&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Build custom modules&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Built a blog and documentation website on Gitpages&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Performing security updates on multiple Drupal websites&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;harvard-magazine&quot;&gt;Harvard Magazine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;associate-web-developer&quot;&gt;Associate Web Developer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Completely rebuilt Harvard Magazine’s classifieds section and their classifieds purchase form with Ubercart&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Restructured how classified ads are stored in the database and displayed to the user&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maintained custom .bash script that created daily back-ups of databases&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/10/21/project-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/10/21/project-2/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project 3</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;cislncar&quot;&gt;CISL/NCAR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-developer-iigraphic-designer&quot;&gt;Web Developer II/Graphic Designer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Utilized Google Analytics to direct front-end improvements&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Train staff on any updates/changes/improvements made to the uploading and editing content process&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Redesigned main menu in the sub-theme to improve usability&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;harvard-magazine&quot;&gt;Harvard Magazine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;associate-web-developer&quot;&gt;Associate Web Developer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Utilized Google Analytics to help filter out trending pages, topics, and events such as email blasts visited on the website to help target advertising opportunities&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Trained staff on any updates/changes/improvements made to the uploading and editing content process&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Restructured our content and gave a training seminar to local staff on SEO best practices and improvements&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/07/30/project-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/07/30/project-3/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project 4</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When working solo, I use the Kanban method to track products from conception to completion. Since implementing this workflow, I have seen a drastic increase both productivity and increased awareness of a current product’s state with product owners. While I have tried several Kanban board tools, I have found JIRA to be the most flexible. Especially as I transition from individual work and group work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have recently been introduced to Scrum while working with a team of four engineers. After attending a recent workshop in Boulder, I’m extreamely exited to dive headfirst into working with a team that focuses on increased software releases, as well as improved code through automated testing (Ghost.js, Slimer.js).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/07/18/project-4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/07/18/project-4/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
